{"id":"2018_25","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"The fear of the Lord is the beginning of knowledge, but fools despise wisdom and instruction.\" â€“ Proverbs 1:7","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.\nUse this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)\nFrom the past week's study, what made the most significant impact on you in the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study?","questions":[]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Proverbs 1.\nProverbs 1-9 offer advice godly parents and mentors can pass on to others.","readVerse":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"1:1-32"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_25_3","questionText":"3. Explain Proverbs 1:7 in your own words. What does it mean to \"fear the Lord\"?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"1:7"}]},{"id":"2018_25_4","questionText":"4. What are some of the benefits of wisdom? Which one is most relevant or comforting to you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_25_5","questionText":"5. Skim Proverbs 2-3 to note a few warnings and commands that stand out to you. Which one calls you to change your response to a current circumstance?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"2:1-3:35"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Proverbs 14 and 16.\nProverbs 10:1-22:16 describe growth in wise living and the costs of foolishness.","readVerse":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"14:1-35"},{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"16:1-33"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_25_6","questionText":"6. How does Proverbs 14 describe a wise person? Which characteristics would you like God to grow in you?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"14:1-35"}]},{"id":"2018_25_7","questionText":"7. What does Proverbs 14 reveal about God? What truth comforts or challenges you most?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"14:1-35"}]},{"id":"2018_25_8","questionText":"8. What truths does Proverbs 16 reveal about speech? How will you practice wise speech in your home, friendships, church and workplace?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"16:1-33"}]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Proverbs 28 and 29.\nProverbs 22:17-29:27 describe good citizenship for community and family life.","readVerse":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"28:1-28"},{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"29:1-27"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_25_9","questionText":"9. Which verses about leadership (rulers) will you apply? How?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_25_10","questionText":"10. Which verses about wealth and poverty will you put into practice? How?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_25_11","questionText":"11. What did you learn about righteous and wicked living? How do these verses challenge or comfort you?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Proverbs 30-31.\nProverbs 30-31 describe observing wisdom in action to learn from others.","readVerse":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"30:1-31:31"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_25_12","questionText":"12. From Proverbs 30, what observations about nature and life are most practical to you? Why?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"30:1-33"}]},{"id":"2018_25_13a","questionText":"13. a. Proverbs 31 personifies wisdom as \"the wife of noble character.\" What aspects of this ideal image stand out to you?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"31:1-31"}]},{"id":"2018_25_13b","questionText":"13. b. How do these descriptions help you recognize wisdom in others and call you to become a wiser member in your family and church?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_25_14","questionText":"14. Which of these verses will you share with those who have been entrusted to your care?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Read Proverbs 1, 14, 16, 28, 29, 30, 31.","readVerse":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"1:1-32"},{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"14:1-35"},{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"16:1-33"},{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"28:1-28"},{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"29:1-27"},{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"30:1-33"},{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"31:1-31"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_25_15","questionText":"15. Choose a few verses from this lesson and think about how the truths line up with your daily actions. Where do you see yourself living out these verses? Where do you see a need for change? Share with your group what God's Word has revealed to you.","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}